Max Obrist Collection
Max Obrist Collection
1914-1923
Obrist, Max.
1.5 linear ft.
Papers of the amateur photographer (1878-1961). Collection includes seventy-nine original glass stereoscopic photographs, a stereoscope, twenty-three single glass plate photographs and a holographic identification list. Photographs were taken in and around St. Gallen, Switzerland by Max Obrist between 1914 and 1923 and include family portraits, architectural shots, a train accident and his father's embroidery factory.
149515
Biographical History
Max Obrist was a Swiss-born American amateur photographer.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Max Obrist Collection consists of autochrome photographs, stereoscopic photographs and miscellaneous.
Autochrome photographs comprises 23 images of Obrist family members and locations in and around St. Gallen, Switzerland.
Stereoscopic photographs consists of seventy-nine original glass clad photographs taken in and around St. Gallen, Switzerland by Max Obrist between 1914 and 1923 and include family portraits, architectural shots, a train accident and his father's embroidery factory.
Miscellaneous consists of a wood and metal stereoscope and a holographic identification list by Mr. Obrist of the stereoscopic images.
Arrangement of the Collection
The autochrome photographs have been given sequential numbers and are listed in that order. The stereoscopic photographs are in sequence by the numbers given them by Mr. Obrist (numbers 1 and 34-53 are not used in that sequence).
Subject and Genre Headings
Photography; Obrist, Max.; Avalanches -- Switzerland -- Photographs.; Color photography.; Embroidery industry -- Switzerland -- Photographs.; Photographers.; Architectural photography.; Photography, Stereoscopic.; Portrait photography.; Swiss Americans.; Travel photography.; Switzerland -- Pictorial works.; Autochromes (photographs); Photographs.; Stereoscopes.; Stereoscopic photographs.; Photographers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Alfred Obrist, 1985.
Inventory
- Autochrome photographs
  - No.1 Carneval, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 2 Carneval, 1923 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 3 Peter & Paul, 1923 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 4 Eidgenössische Turnfest, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 5 Eidgenössische Turnfest, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 6 No. 5 Eidgenössische Turnfest, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 7 Convent Stein, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 8 Stein, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 9 Living room, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 10 Säntis, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 11 Carneval, 1923 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 12 Gerhalde, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 13 Heiligkreuz, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 14 Thur Schwarzenbach, 1923 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 15 Thur N'büren, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 16 Pear tree, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 17 The kids, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 18 Sitterwald, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 19 Miriam, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 20 Roses, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 21 Ebnat, 1922 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 22 Spring flowers, 1923 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 23 Miriam, 1922 (Oversize 1)
- Stereoscopic photographs
  - No. 2 Miriam Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 3 Mary Obrist and friend, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 4 Obrist family gathering, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 5 Mary Obrist and Miriam Obrist ?, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 6 Mary Obrist and Miriam Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 7 Max, Miriam and Alfred Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 8 Max and Mary obrist with Miriam and Alfred, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 9 Scene in the Alps, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 10 Miriam Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 11 Obrist family, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 12 Max Obrist with Miriam, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 13 Mary Obrist with Alfred, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 14 Miriam Obrist and snowman, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 15 Mary Obrist with Miriam, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 16 Mary Obrist with Miriam, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 17 Mary Obrist with Miriam, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 18 Miriam Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 19 Mary Obrist with Alfred, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 20 Max and Mary Obrist with Miriam, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 21 Miriam Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 22 Two women, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 23 Alfred Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 24 Miriam Obrist and dog, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 25 Street scene, men with donkey, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 26 Skiers, Mary Obrist and Miriam (in Davos?), undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 27 Scene in the Alps, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 28 Max Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 29 Scene in the Alps, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 30 Miriam and Alfred Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 31 House interior St. Gallen, Switzerland, 1921 (Oversize 1)
  - No. 32 Miriam Obrist (with bow) and two friends, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 33 Grospapa and carriage (Jacob Obrist), undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 53 Railroad accident (avalanche), undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 54 Railroad accident (avalanche), undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 55 Railroad accident (avalanche), undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 56 Swiss farmhouse, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 57 Colonnade, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 58 Railroad accident (avalanche), undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 59 Dog lying in doorway, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 60 House of Jacob Obrist St. Gallen, Switzerland, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 61 Library at St. Gallen, Switzerland, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 62 Mary Obrist and Miriam (at far right), undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 63 Sleeping Lion monument Lucerne, Switzerland, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 64 Martha Volpius and Alfred Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 65 Docked sailing ships, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 66 Swiss embroidery factory, St Gallen, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 67 Interior of Obrist house St. Gallen, Switzerland, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 6 Bullfighting arena Barcelona, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 69 Choir stall St. Gallen Cathedral St. Gallen, Switzerland, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 70 Max Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 71 Mary Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 72 Forest trail, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 73 Wildflowers, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 74 Forest scene, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 75 Jacob Obrist house, St. Gallen, Switzerland, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 76 Tree-lined road, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 77 Obrist family?, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 78 Miriam Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 79 Winter forest scene, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 80 Max Obrist house, St. Gallen, Switzerland, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 81 Alfred Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 82 Miriam Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 83 Street scene with donkey and cart, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 84 Interior of Max Obrist house, St. Gallen, Switzerland, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 85 Wildflowers, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 86 Street scene with church in background, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 87 River and bridge, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 88 Winter village scene, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 89 Max Obrist and child sitting on rail fence, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 90 Street scene, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 91 Covered bridge, Lausanne, Switzerland, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 92 Covered bridge, Lausanne, Switzerland, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 93 Two boys with goats, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 94 Miriam Obrist, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 95 Max and Miriam Obrist in the Alps, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 96 Scene in the Alps, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 97 Houses in the Alps, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 98 Cathedral courtyard, St. Gallen, Switzerland, undated (Oversize 1)
  - No. 99 Embroidery factory, undated (Oversize 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Handwritten list of stereoscopic photographs, undated (Oversize 1)
  - Wood and metal stereoscope, undated (Oversize 1)